

Thai Nguyen Hien Thao Legal Intern

Contact

- 0917210134
- Maril hienthaoulaw@gmail.com
- Dien Bien Phu Street, Binh Thanh District, HCM City
- Iinkedin.com/in/hiền-thảo-68baa0218

About Me

A passionate, responsible and eager to learn student, on the journey to find real legal work opportunities in a professional environment.

Skills

Main skills

 Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, Powerpoint)

Soft skills

- Negotiation
- Critical Thinking
- Drafting contracts
- Effective time management
- Honesty, integrity, carefulness

Language

• English: Toeic 600

• French: A2

Career goals

Short-term goal: Apply knowledge and skills learned at school to complete and further develop as a Legal intern.

Long-term goal: Accumulate experience and continuously develop yourself in a professional working environment, become proficient in the law field, and become a Legal consultant in 5 years.

Education



BACHELOR OF COMMERCIAL LAW

Ho Chi Minh University of Law 2020- 2024

Experience

Legal intern at Phap Ly Viet Law firm

2/2024-6/2024

- Support and carry out legal procedures and submit documents to agencies and departments.
- Support reviewing and drafting contracts, agreements and related legal documents.
- Support research and review of legal documents of civil cases.
- Research legal documents, legal issues and update new legal regulations.

Legal intern at An Luat Law firm

9/2024-11/2024

- Research legal documents, legal issues and update new legal regulations.
- Support drafting legal documents in contracts.
- Research and advise on legal issues in labor contracts.
- Check and review labor contracts.

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Collaborator of French Club - Faculty Delegation High quality training programs at Ho Chi Minh City University of Law.

 Content team leader, responsible for coming up with ideas, planning, writing articles and communicating for the club's program activities. Support in solving problems about events, movements, and plans of the club.

Organizing committee of the charity event "LES PETITES FLEURS"

 Planning and organizing a charity fundraising event with 50 members of the French Club, we gave gifts to the children at Minh Tam Shelter (District 12 - Ho Chi Minh City).



Thái Nguyễn Hiền Thảo

Thực tập sinh pháp lý

Contact

- **** 0917210134
- ★ hienthaoulaw@gmail.com
- Bạch Đằng, Quận Bình Thạnh, TPHCM
- linkedin.com/in/hiền-thảo-68baa0218

Giới thiệu

Một sinh viên đam mê, có trách nhiệm và ham học hỏi đang trên hành trình tìm kiếm cơ hội, kinh nghiệm làm việc pháp lý thực tế trong môi trường chuyên nghiệp.

Kỹ năng

Kỹ năng cứng

 Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, Powerpoint)

Kỹ năng mềm

- Nghiên cứu pháp luật
- Tư duy phản biện
- Kỹ năng soạn thảo
- Kỹ năng giao tiếp tốt
- Kỹ năng đàm phán
- kỹ năng quản lý thời gian

Ngôn ngữ

- Tiếng anh: Toeic 600
- Tiếng pháp: A2

Mục tiêu nghề nghiệp

Mục tiêu ngắn hạn: Áp dụng kiến thức và kỹ năng đã học ở trường để hoàn thành và phát triển hơn nữa ở vị trí thực tập sinh pháp lý.

Mục tiêu dài hạn: Tích lũy kinh nghiệm, không ngừng học hỏi và phát triển bản thân trong môi trường chuyên nghiệp, thành thạo lĩnh vực pháp luật và trở thành chuyên gia tư vấn pháp luật trong 5 năm.

Học vấn



Cử nhân Luật Thương mại Đại học Luật TPHCM

2020-2024

Kinh Nghiệm

Thực tập sinh tại Công ty TNHH Pháp Lý Việt 3/2024-6/2024

- Hỗ trợ và thực hiện các thủ tục pháp lý và nộp hồ sơ cho các cơ quan, ban ngành.
- Hỗ trợ rà soát, soạn thảo hợp đồng, thỏa thuận và các văn bản pháp lý liên quan.
- Hỗ trợ nghiên cứu, rà soát văn bản pháp lý của các vụ án dân sự.
- Nghiên cứu văn bản pháp lý, các vấn đề pháp lý và cập nhật các quy định pháp lý mới.

Thực tập sinh tại Công ty Luật TNHH An Luật 9/2024- 11/2024

- Nghiên cứu các văn bản pháp lý, các vấn đề pháp lý và cập nhật các quy định pháp lý mới.
- Hỗ trợ soạn thảo các tài liệu pháp lý trong hợp đồng
- Nghiên cứu và tư vấn các vấn đề pháp lý trong hợp đồng lao động.
- Kiểm tra và rà soát các hợp đồng lao động.

Hoạt động ngoại khóa

Cộng tác viên Câu lạc bộ Tiếng Pháp - Đoàn Khoa Chương trình đào tạo chất lượng cao tại Đại học Luật TP.HCM.

- Trưởng nhóm nội dung, chịu trách nhiệm lên ý tưởng, lập kế hoạch, viết bài và truyền thông cho các hoạt động chương trình của câu lạc bộ.
- Hỗ trợ giải quyết các vướng mắc về các sự kiện, phong trào, kế hoach của CLB.

Ban tổ chức sự kiện từ thiện "LES PETITES FLEURS"

 Lên kế hoạch và tổ chức cùng với 50 thành viên Câu lạc bộ Tiếng Pháp, gửi tặng những phần quà cho các em nhỏ tại Mái ấm Minh Tâm (Quận 12 - TP.HCM).